# GIUSEPPE MELE

Software Engineer

1-630-429-5738

Phoenix, AZ

www.giuseppemele.com

ggmele1@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

I am a self-motivated Software Engineer with a passion for building complex systems and solving problems. I merge my usability and user experience expertise to design, develop, test, maintain and deploy applications. My repertoire includes technologies such as JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, and a notable skill set for design and prototyping.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Front End Software Engineer Freelance

2018 - Current

- Engineer and build responsive web applications with JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Utilize React, Redux, Node.js, and Express.js to develop highly usable and cleanly written interfaces
- Create and design high fidelity UX/UI prototypes
- Deploy & manage apps with AWS and Heroku

## Graphic Designer / Web Developer

**Wynn Resorts Las Vegas** 

Las Vegas, NV

Jan 2019 - July 2020

- Designed, created, and revised digital assets across a variety of platforms, including: social media, websites, emails, and digital ads
- Automated a process to create and deliver graphics in bulk using data-driven graphics and increasing productivity from seven days to one
- Developed landing pages and HTML emails using modern web technologies
- Mastered Abobe Photoshop

## **SKILLS**

#### Front-end

JavaScript | React | Redux | TypeScript | HTML5 |
CSS3 | SASS | LESS | jQuery | Webpack | AJAX | ES6

#### Back-end

Express.js | Node.js | MongoDB | PostgreSQL

#### Other

Version Control (Git) | Unit Testing | Jest | OOP |

API | Rest | NPM | UX/UI | Adobe Creative Cloud

## **PROJECTS**

### Spot My Taste

<a href="https://www.giuseppemele.com/project/spotmytaste">https://www.giuseppemele.com/project/spotmytaste</a>

- A front-end application built with Spotify's REST API that accesses a user's Spotify data and displays their most-listened-to tracks and artists over a given time period.
- Utilizes OAuth 2.0 to authenticate a user and grant access to Spotify, as well as the users own data.
- Tools used: React JS, AJAX, Axios, Material UI, GitHub Pages.

### Dopest Data

₱ https://www.giuseppemele.com/project/dopestdata

- A front-end React application users can search specific cannabis strains and retrieve information such as effects, similar strains and a description.
- Data is stored in a custom Google Firebase realtime database and uses the Firebase JS SDK to read and write data upon request.
- Tools used: React JS, react-router, JSX, Firebase, axios, javaScript, gh-pages.

#### Xplor

₱ https://www.giuseppemele.com/project/xplor

- A full-stack social media application that allows users to create an account, login, post, and like other users' posts.
- Built using the MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React JS, Node.js) stack and authenticates users with a JSON web token
- Tools used: AWS, Redux, React-Router, JWT. AJAX.

## **EDUCATION**

Associate's Degree College Of Dupage 2014 - 2016

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Digital Marketing Certification**General Assembly
2018